Giulia Mumnolo

Frontend Developer

(+44) 7426490423
giuliamummolo.com
mail@giuliamummolo.com
London - Lisbon

Main skills

UI design
Frontend web development
Product
Team management
Time management
E-Commerce

Tool box

React.js

NextJS

JavaScript

Typescript

Storybook

CSS-in-Js

Material UI Firebase

Jest

Figma

Jira

Gitlab

Git

Wordpress Shopify

Languages

Italian (Native) English (Advanced) Portuguese (Basic) I am a frontend web developer and UI designer with a background in fashion design and professional experience in retail and e-commerce.

My background in design and analytical mind allows me to work at the intersection between UI design and code. I have experience in building interactive and accessible user interfaces within the Javascript ecosystem.

As a people-oriented person, I thrive in a collaborative environment and collectively solve challenges.

Experience

Frontend Engineer at Farfetch

May 2022 - Present

Lisbon

- Designed and implemented the internal developer docs
- Implemented customer-facing features for client's e-stores
- Contributed to open-source SDKs

HTML - CSS-in-Js - React - Next.js - JavaScript - Typescript - Jest - Storybook

UI Designer and Web Developer at The Clothing Loop

Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

Amsterdam (remote)

- Development of React and Typescript web application for a clothing exchange initiative (view project here and repository here)
- Designed and coded the UI
- Built and enabled a team of 5 volunteer web developers

React - JavaScript - Typescript - Firebase - Sass - Material UI

E-Commerce Executive at Georgiana Scott

London

Feb 2019 - Oct 2020

- Planned and executed marketing campaigns which doubled total page views
- Improved bounce rate by 20% through a website redesign, marketing campaigns and SEO
- Managed a Shopify E-Commerce
- Liaising with web developers

Further Experience

Sales and Product Major at Moncler

Jan 2018 - Feb 2019

London

First point of contact for Moncler own products within the Harrods concession. Managing product cycle including stock maintenance, movements across Europe, aftercare services and customer inquiries.

Brand Manager at Harrods

May 2015 - Jan 2018

London

Responsible for the overall performance within the kidswear division of Moncler products through sales and stock management.

Sales Advisor at Bottega Veneta

Sept 2014 - April 2015

London

Part-time role covered while completing my BA degree course. Sales in a target-driven environment with a focus on private clients.

Store Supervisor at Banana Republic

May 2012 - Aug 2014

London

Part-time role covered while completing my BA degree course. Supervised a team of 20 across several roles within a KPIs-based environment.

Education

CodersInHoods - Coding Bootcamp

March - June 2020

London

Kodiri - Coding Bootcamp

Aug - Oct 2019

London

BA(hons) Fashion Design - Istituto Marangoni

2013 - 2016

London